<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://connorbaer.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://connorbaer.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-07T18:51:00+02:00</updated><id>http://connorbaer.io/</id><title>Made by Connor.</title><subtitle>Designer, developer &amp; traveller. Embrace change.</subtitle><author><name>Connor Bär</name><email>hello@connorbaer.io</email></author><entry><title>This is the Europe I am proud of.</title><link href="http://connorbaer.io/this-is-the-europe-i-am-proud-of/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is the Europe I am proud of." /><published>2015-09-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://connorbaer.io/this-is-the-europe-i-am-proud-of</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://connorbaer.io/this-is-the-europe-i-am-proud-of/">&lt;p&gt;I am in tears. Finally (!) Austria and Germany show some compassion and welcome refugees. The outpouring of support for refugees is humbling. “By Saturday afternoon, officials in Vienna had to ask people to stay away from the train station, which was heavily overcrowded with well-wishers bearing donations.” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/sep/05/refugee-crisis-warm-welcome-for-people-bussed-from-budapest&quot;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Now we are breathing the air of freedom here.” — Wahid, a Syrian refugee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the Europe I want. This is the Europe I am proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Politicians insist that this is an exception, nonetheless it is a step in the right direction. Quite in contrast are the reactions in Hungary where a new border fence is being erected and heavily-equipped police encircle exhausted refugees to deport them to camps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/06/opinion/sunday/the-refugee-crisis-isnt-a-european-problem.html&quot;&gt;Michael Ignatieff&lt;/a&gt; brings it to the point: “What’s holding back sympathy for the Syrians? They’ve been barrel-bombed in Aleppo by their own regime, they’ve been tortured, kidnapped and massacred by miscellaneous jihadis and opposition militias. They’ve been in refugee camps for years, waiting for that cruelly deceiving fiction “the international community” to come to their aid. Now, when they take to the roads, to the boats and to the trains, all our political leaders can think of is fences, barbed wire and more police.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hungary’s President Orban warned of a “Muslim threat” to a Christian culture and insist that Europe should close its borders or otherwise the inflow of refugees would increase. This kind of thinking is highly dangerous and ignorant. It is not the prospect of ‘heavenly’ Europe that causes refugees to cross the Mediterranean Sea in overloaded boats, it is the deterrent, inhumane and unbearable state of their home countries. No matter how ‘unattractive’ we make Europe, anything is better than life in a refugee camp in the middle of a war zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to forget that we are partially responsible for that, too. If we’ve been arming Syrian rebels, shouldn’t we also be helping the people trying to get out of their way? If we’ve failed to broker peace in Syria, can’t we help the people who can’t wait for peace any longer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I was in Germany so I could help out, too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Connor Bär</name><email>hello@connorbaer.io</email></author><summary>I am in tears. Finally (!) Austria and Germany show some compassion and welcome refugees. The outpouring of support for refugees is humbling. “By Saturday afternoon, officials in Vienna had to ask people to stay away from the train station, which was heavily overcrowded with well-wishers bearing donations.” (The Guardian)</summary></entry><entry><title>Africa is not a country.</title><link href="http://connorbaer.io/africa-is-not-a-country/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Africa is not a country." /><published>2015-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://connorbaer.io/africa-is-not-a-country</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://connorbaer.io/africa-is-not-a-country/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20061027224128AAFtJ8D&quot;&gt;Why is Africa not a country?&lt;/a&gt; Guess what, it’s a continent. It consists of 55 individual countries, yet western journalists insist on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jan/24/africa-clinton&quot;&gt;referring to it as one place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They generally don’t differentiate between the unique cultures of Botswana and Mauritania, even though they are about as different and far away from each other as the United States and Brazil. They portrait Africa is one big country characterized by HIV/AIDS, poverty, pirates, civil war, famines — the only exceptions perhaps being the north (the region of the Arab spring) and South Africa with elephants and giraffes grazing in front of deep red sunsets. Oh yeah, and the 2010 Soccer World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;photo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this photo was taken in Africa. But it is wrong to reduce ‘Africa’ to big eyes and poverty. There is so much more to the continent and each country is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding to that image are charities with their ads of incredibly cute black children living in round huts, their big eyes starring sadly into the camera. The next time you throw your change into the donation jar at a supermarket, think about this first: often charities will use your money to give out free goods to families in need. Seems perfectly fine, but it actually destroys the local economy. Why should a family spend money on shoes if it knows that it will receive free ones? The local shoe industry loses its customers and goes bankrupt, leaving more people unemployed and unable to support their families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charities are selling the idea of a starving Africa, yet it is full of potential. There are still many obstacles to overcome but I am convinced that Africa will developed rapidly over the next few decades, some parts more than others. Things are done differently here and it would be wrong to say that the European or American way is better. What Africa needs is time to adjust in its own pace, according to its own customs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Shoot me a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/connor_baer&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;! I’d love to hear your opinions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Connor Bär</name><email>hello@connorbaer.io</email></author><summary>Why is Africa not a country? Guess what, it’s a continent. It consists of 55 individual countries, yet western journalists insist on referring to it as one place.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://connorbaer.iozebra" /></entry><entry><title>“Nobody has the intention of building an airport!”*</title><link href="http://connorbaer.io/nobody-has-the-intention-of-building-an-airport/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="“Nobody has the intention of building an airport!”*" /><published>2013-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2013-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://connorbaer.io/nobody-has-the-intention-of-building-an-airport</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://connorbaer.io/nobody-has-the-intention-of-building-an-airport/">&lt;p&gt;Those were the words that passed through my mind when I got on the impossibly crowded bus to Berlin Tegel airport. I’ve never seen so many people unintentionally hugging each other. I started to fully understand the tragedy behind the disaster that some people call &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.berlin-airport.de/en/index.php&quot;&gt;Berlin Brandenburg Airport&lt;/a&gt;. Not only did I understand it, I could also feel it painfully in the form of an elbow in my back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally got off the bus after what felt like an hour the delight of being at an airport washed away my discontent. I made my way through the travellers, snagged a chocolate heart that stewardesses of Air Berlin handed out and looked out for my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arzucanaskin.com/&quot;&gt;Arzu&lt;/a&gt;. She was the reason I was at the airport. In about an hour she would board the Airbus A321 to Istanbul and then continue her journey to Hong Kong where she would attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lpcuwc.edu.hk/&quot;&gt;Li Po Chun United World College&lt;/a&gt; for two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t the only one who wanted to wave goodbye to her: Numerous friends and her family were already waiting with her, taking a last photo, crying and hugging each other. Together we brought her to gate 4. We didn’t stop waiving until she had passed through the security check and we couldn’t see her anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That moment I realized what was going on. She was really leaving. I wouldn’t see her for probably two years. She was gone. Far away. She would discover new things, meet new friends, and have the time of her life while I still had to wait three month till &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.waterford.sz/&quot;&gt;Swaziland&lt;/a&gt;. Three long and boring month. But wait…that isn’t true! I have an exciting time ahead of me, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I’m going to start an internship at the office of the German UWC National Committee, focusing on raising awareness for UWC among students through social media marketing — a topic that fascinates me. I already have an enormous list of ideas that I just can’t wait to try! On top of that I’m living on my own for the first time in my life. In Berlin! Like it could get any more exciting than that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;*Reference to the famous quote from 1961 by Walter Ulbricht, then head of state of the German Democratic Republic: “Nobody has the intention of building a wall!” — two month later work began on what was to become the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berlin_Wall&quot;&gt;Berlin Wall&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment workers and politicians struggle to finish the new Berlin Brandenburg airport that is supposed to replace the two old airports Tegel &amp;amp; Schönefeld and should have started operation over a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Connor Bär</name><email>hello@connorbaer.io</email></author><summary>Those were the words that passed through my mind when I got on the impossibly crowded bus to Berlin Tegel airport. I’ve never seen so many people unintentionally hugging each other. I started to fully understand the tragedy behind the disaster that some people call Berlin Brandenburg Airport. Not only did I understand it, I could also feel it painfully in the form of an elbow in my back.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://connorbaer.ioairport" /></entry></feed>
